Mars Geldard

♀ Roslyn Avenue, Kingston Beach, Tasmania, 7050 □ +61 (0) 431 521 961

Professional Summary_

Career Objectives

I aim to become proficient in a wide range of technologies, expand upon my abilities as a programmer and designer, and add to my experience in mentorship and research. In the pursuit of these goals I hope to always surround myself with opportunities to learn and share my knowledge with others.

Career Summary

In the past I have had somewhat varied experience, having been in the workforce for over 8 years before entering tertiary study. Coming from a non-technical background, I quickly found my passion for technology as a way to express my love of mathematics and obsessions with problem-solving and optimisation.

Education

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology

Mid 2016 - Current

University of Tasmania (UTAS)

Second Year Student

- Bachelor majoring in Software Development
- Electives focusing on Human-Computer Interaction and Research
- Completed 1/3 elite Summer research units: KIT110 under the supervision of Dr Kristy de Salas

Entry requirements for Bachelor's Degree

Start 2016 - Mid 2016

UTAS University Preparation Program

Fast-Tracked

- Completed units on topics such as academic writing, communication and study skills
- Fast-tracked to Bachelor after completing one semester of the 2-semester course

Secondary School/Junior Certificate

2005 - Start 2009

Kimberley College

Left to work

- Completed junior certificate, majoring in the technical stream (Mathematics, Biology, Chemistry, Physics)

Experience_____

Bar and Gaming Attendant, Office Assistant

Mid 2012 - End 2015

Sherwood Services Club

Resigned

Initially being hired as a bartender, it was not long before the vast majority of my work was as a gaming cashier, controlling the cash flow within the club, or assisting in the admin/accounts office. My duties as a cashier included swapping money and making change for customers and other areas of the club, counting and sorting tills, making payouts to gaming winners, and assisting managers with all manner of paperwork.

This was fast-paced work that required and bred precision above all else. My time in the admin office had me working both as an office assistant, filing and submitting paperwork, but also dealing with incoming stock, wages and account transactions and their associated software.

Supervisor/Co-ordinator

2009 - Mid 2012

 $Elstern\ Imports$

Resigned

Starting off at the company when I was 15, I was hired as a casual picker & packer for a wholesale-only jewellery and medical supplies distribution company. In the time that I was there I rose to hire and supervise 4 other staff (and the whole division of our company that dealt with our chain customers), as the company grew to not only have more wholesale customers than ever, but also run 2 retail web-stores.

My daily tasks were overseeing orders and dispatch, generating digital and hand-written invoices, ordering and receiving of stock from our suppliers, taking complaints, inquiries and orders via phone/email/fax, and managing the bar-coding and stock systems for our end of the warehouse (including implementing a new system when our number of stock lines outgrew the old one), along with many other unique tasks that would crop up every day.

September 19, 2017 Mars Geldard Résumé 1

Awards & Interests

PRIZES & PARTICIPATIONS

Memberships

Volunteering & Conferences

Hobbies & Community Involvement

Tasmanian technology and game development communities

Various Groups 2016 - Current

Local Community Member

- Frequent attendee and volunteer at local events, both technical- and networking-focused (e.g. ACS events, TasICT events, independent events held at Enterprize or Factory Floor)

 Member of TasGDS, a society dedicated to facilitating the networking and sharing of ideas among both professional and independent game developers in Tasmania

Referees

Tony Gray

Character Reference - Organiser of /dev/world

Peter Ward

Professional Reference - Previous Employer

Valerie Ford

Character Reference - Lifelong Family Friend

Chair, Apple University Consortium 0432 018 441 — a.d.gray@utas.edu.au

Owner/GM, Sherwood Services Club Reference attached

Legal Aid Queensland 0407 594 427 — vjford22@hotmail.com

September 19, 2017 Mars Geldard Résumé 2